<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Numworks on Zardam&#39;s home</title>
    <link>https://zardam.github.io/tags/numworks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Numworks on Zardam&#39;s home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:42:51 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zardam.github.io/tags/numworks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NumWorks UART Over USB port</title>
      <link>https://zardam.github.io/post/numworks-uart-over-usb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:42:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zardam.github.io/post/numworks-uart-over-usb/</guid>
      <description>Some people are complaining about the lack of connectivity to the outside world from the calculator, but in fact it is pretty simple to change that.
According to the calculator schematics, the USB port of the calculator is wired to PA11 and PA12 of the STM32F412. We have this in the datasheet about these pins :
So, it is possible to map an UART on the USB port D+ and D-.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenOCD on the Raspberry Pi inside a NumWorks calculator</title>
      <link>https://zardam.github.io/post/raspberrypi-numworks-openocd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 21:18:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zardam.github.io/post/raspberrypi-numworks-openocd/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I added a Raspberry Pi Zero inside the calculator. Why not use also it to program/debug the calculator firmware ?
What I have done is basically to follow this adafruit tutorial.
I soldered only SWDIO to Raspberry Pi #24 and SWCLK to Raspberry Pi #25. This seems to be enough, and the reset button of the calculator is not far away if needed.
Using the following OpenOCD script, it is now possible to debug or program the calculator over the air !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Raspberry Pi inside a NumWorks calculator</title>
      <link>https://zardam.github.io/post/raspberrypi-numworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zardam.github.io/post/raspberrypi-numworks/</guid>
      <description>I was having a Raspberry Pi Zero sitting on my desk for a long time, searching for something to do with it. I also wanted to to learm STM32, mainly DMA and interrups. As the caculator is powered by an STM32F412, why not put them together ?
TL;DR, the result:   The idea was to add an application on the calculator, which will display the output of the Raspberry Pi, and send keystroke from the keyboard to it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>